<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dr. Janina Pawelz on Dr. Janina Pawelz</title>
    <link>http://janinapawelz.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dr. Janina Pawelz on Dr. Janina Pawelz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 15:23:46 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://janinapawelz.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 19:23:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://janinapawelz.com/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;vita&#34;&gt;Vita&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janina Pawelz is a researcher and joined the IFSH in 2017. Previously, she was a postdoctoral fellow at the GIGA Institute for Asian Studies. She received her doctorate (2013-2016) from the GIGA German Institute of Global and Area Studies. At the GIGA she was a member of the “Peace and Security” research program, the &amp;ldquo;Identities, Ideology, and Conflict&amp;rdquo; research team and also held the position of Deputy Equal Opportunities Officer. Janina Pawelz studied political science, Austronesian studies and ethnology at the University of Hamburg and the Universitas Udayana, Indonesia. She worked for the Deutsche Gesellschaft für Internationale Zusammenarbeit (GIZ) as an international consultant. She was an election observer in Timor-Leste in 2012 and is a member of the ZIF Expert Pool for Election Observation (Center for International Peace Operations - ZIF).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;research-profile--current-projects&#34;&gt;Research Profile | Current Projects&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janina Pawelz conducts research on political, collective and urban violence, social peace and radicalization with a special focus on youth, youth violence and non-violent conflict transformation. At the IFSH, she works on radicalization in the Salafist and extreme right spectrum. Her main focus is on how these phenomena manifest in social media. Further research interests in the field of peace and security include the dynamics of violence, gangs and transformation processes of violent groups, forms of legitimacy and control of armed actors and their claim to power, and exercise of power from a comparative perspective. For her doctoral thesis on the transformation of violent groups, she spent six months conducting field research in Southeast Asia and the Caribbean where she interviewed members of violent groups. She is interested in empirical methods, field research, development cooperation and monitoring and evaluation (M&amp;amp;E).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://janinapawelz.com/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 19:23:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://janinapawelz.com/publications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;journal-articles&#34;&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pawelz, Janina.&lt;/strong&gt; 2020.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ojs.panteion.gr/?journal=uc&amp;amp;page=article&amp;amp;op=view&amp;amp;path%5B%5D=245&amp;amp;path%5B%5D=229&#34;&gt;In bed with criminals: Gangs and politics in Trinidad and Tobago.&lt;/a&gt;
Urban Crime. An international Journal 1 (2): 54-75.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marcks, Holger, Janina Pawelz. 2020.
From Myths of Victimhood to Fantasies of Violence: How Far-Right Narratives of Imperilment Work.
Terrorism and Political Violence DOI: 10.1080/09546553.2020.1788544.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Birsl, Ursula, Martin Kahl, Janina Pawelz. 2018.
Propaganda, Mobilisierung und Radikalisierung zur Gewalt.
Forum Kriminalprävention 2: 29-31.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pawelz, Janina. 2018.
Researching Gangs: How to Reach Hard-to-Reach Populations and Negotiate Tricky Issues in the Field.
Forum Qualitative Sozialforschung 19 (1) DOI: 10.17169/fqs-19.1.2878.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pawelz, Janina. 2018.
Fürsorge und Terror. Über Gangherrschaft in Trinidad und Tobago.
Mittelweg 36 27 (2): 86-105.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pawelz, Janina. 2018.
Hobsbawm in Trinidad: Understanding Contemporary Modalities of Urban Violence.
Conflict, Security &amp;amp; Development 18 (5): 409-432. DOI: 10.1080/14678802.2018.1511165.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pawelz, Janina, Anja Schmidt-Kleinert. 2018.
Editorial zum Schwerpunkt &amp;ldquo;Radikalisierung&amp;rdquo;.
Demokratie gegen Menschenfeindlichkeit 2: 8-10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pawelz, Janina, Paul Elvers. 2018.
The Digital Hood of Urban Violence: Exploring Functionalities of Social Media and Music Among Gangs.
Journal of Contemporary Criminal Justice 34 (4): 442–459. DOI: 10.1177/1043986218787735.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kurtenbach, Sabine, Janina Pawelz. 2015.
Voting is not enough: youth and political citizenship in post-war societies.
Peacebuilding 3 (2): 141-156. DOI: 10.1080/21647259.2015.1052629.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pawelz, Janina. 2015.
Security, Violence, and Outlawed Martial Arts Groups in Timor-Leste.
Asian Journal of Peacebuilding 3 (1): 121-136.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;book-chapters&#34;&gt;Book Chapters&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fielitz, Maik, Janina Pawelz. 2020.
Die extreme Rechte und politische Bildungsarbeit in der digitalen Gesellschaft.
In: Aufruhr in der Echo-Kammer. Fragestellungen und Analysen zum Thema medienpädagogische Interventionen im Feld der Neuen Rechten. Expertise Nr. 1, edited by Fabian Kaufmann, Lena Sierts, 35-44. Hamburg: CJD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pawelz, Janina. 2019.
Well-known and little understood: martial arts groups in Timor-Leste.
In: Routledge Handbook of Contemporary Timor-Leste, edited by Andrew McWilliam, Michael Leach, 197-209. London: Routledge.
Pawelz, Janina. 2013.
Osttimor.
In: Sozialpolitik in Entwicklungsländern. Asien, Afrika. Lateinamerika - Ein Handbuch, edited by Markus Porsche-Ludwig, Wolfgang Gieler, Jürgen Bellers, 271-277. Berlin: LIT-Verlag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pawelz, Janina. 2013.
Osttimor.
In: Handbuch Sozialpolitiken der Welt, edited by Markus Porsche-Ludwig, Wolfgang Gieler, Jürgen Bellers, 455-460. Berlin: LIT-Verlag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pawelz, Janina. 2013.
Osttimor.
In: Sozialpolitik in Asien. Ein Handbuch der Staaten Asiens von A-Z, edited by Markus Porsche-Ludwig, Jürgen Bellers, Wolfgang Gieler, 153-159. Berlin: LIT-Verlag.
Pawelz, Janina. 2013.
Osttimor.
In: Wirtschaftshandbuch Asien-Pazifik 2012/2013, edited by Ostasiatischer Verein, 535-548. Hamburg: German Asia-Pacific Business Association.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;working-papers-and-policy-briefs&#34;&gt;Working Papers and Policy Briefs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pawelz, Janina. 2020.
Aux armes! Der digitale Kampf gegen Rechtsextremismus im Internet.
Policy Brief 4/2020. Hamburg: IFSH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pawelz, Janina. 2015.
Der Rückzug von Premierminister Gusmão: Politische Weichenstellung in Timor-Leste.
GIGA Focus Asien 02. Hamburg: GIGA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pawelz, Janina, Henri Myrttinen. 2012.
Wahlen in Timor-Leste: Feuerprobe für Sicherheit und Konsolidierung.
GIGA Focus Asien 07. Hamburg: GIGA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;commentaries-and-other-publications&#34;&gt;Commentaries and other Publications&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pawelz, Janina. 2020.
Außen Robin Hood, innen Al Capone.
In: Internationale Politik und Gesellschaft&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pawelz, Janina. 2020.
Why Coronavirus gives organized crime momentum to shine and flourish.
In: Urban Violence Research Network: Word on the Street&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marcks, Holger, Janina Pawelz. 2020.
What Makes Far-Right Rhetoric so Dangerous?.
In: PRIF Blog&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marcks, Holger, Janina Pawelz. 2020.
What Makes Far-Right Rhetoric So Dangerous? Narratives of Imperilment as Justification of Violence.
In: The Global Network on Extremism and Technology (GNET), Insights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marcks, Holger, Janina Pawelz. 2020.
Der Stoff, aus dem Gewaltfantasien sind.
In: Geschichte der Gegenwart&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pawelz, Janina. 2017.
Timor-Leste.
In: Munzinger-Archiv&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pawelz, Janina. 2011.
Timor-Leste.
In: Munzinger-Archiv&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>http://janinapawelz.com/posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 15:23:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://janinapawelz.com/posts/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>